<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Sameer Totey</title>
 <link href="http://www.sameertotey.com/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://www.sameertotey.com/"/>
 <updated>2015-03-20T14:17:28-06:00</updated>
 <id>http://www.sameertotey.com</id>
 <author>
   <name>Sameer Totey</name>
   <email></email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>My First iOS App on the App Store</title>
   <link href="http://www.sameertotey.com/2015/03/20/my-first-ios-app/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-20T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.sameertotey.com/2015/03/20/my-first-ios-app</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;I am very excited to report that my very first iOS app is now available on the &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/blackjack-configurable/id975037070?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;App Store&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;message&quot;&gt;
Please use the game and review it on the App Store.
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/blackjack-configurable/id975037070?ls=1&amp;amp;mt=8&quot;&gt;Blackjack-Configurable&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#39;s a iOS app written in Swift. All graphics and animation for the game was done using the iOS UIKit framework. The game is integrated with &lt;a href=&quot;https://developer.apple.com/game-center/&quot;&gt;Apple&amp;#39;s game center&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It is a &lt;a href=&quot;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blackjack&quot;&gt;Blackjack card game&lt;/a&gt; with configurable rules. You can practice blackjack strategy by easily setting rules applicable to any blackjack establishment. Plenty of configuration options are available.  &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;Open Source&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The app is completely free and open source.  You can check the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/sameertotey/BlackJack&quot;&gt;Github repo&lt;/a&gt; to view all the source code. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Configuration options&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have spend great effort to ensure that all the Blackjack game rules are applied accurately. Since there are so many variations of the Blackjack game, I have created easy configuration settings to set the desired rules.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Future plans&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I plan to add more features to this game in the future releases, please stay tuned for updates. In the meanwhile visit the app&amp;#39;s &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sameertotey.com/BlackJack/&quot;&gt;support site&lt;/a&gt; to learn how to play the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>My Personal Journal</title>
   <link href="http://www.sameertotey.com/2015/03/19/my-personal-journal/"/>
   <updated>2015-03-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
   <id>http://www.sameertotey.com/2015/03/19/my-personal-journal</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Welcome&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have deciced to chronicle my personal observations about software development on this personal journal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This blog was constructed using &lt;a href=&quot;http://jekyllrb.com&quot;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt; a static site generator, an open-source tool for creating simple yet powerful websites of all shapes and sizes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have adapted the styles from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/poole/hyde&quot;&gt;Hyde&lt;/a&gt;. Hyde is a brazen two-column Jekyll theme that pairs a prominent sidebar with uncomplicated content. It&amp;#39;s based on &lt;a href=&quot;http://getpoole.com&quot;&gt;Poole&lt;/a&gt;, the Jekyll butler. The overall concept of this blog is inspired from &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/barryclark/jekyll-now&quot;&gt;Jekyll now&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The blog is hosted on &lt;a href=&quot;https://pages.github.com/&quot;&gt;Github Pages&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
